# Shivani Doshi

shivanidoshi26@gmail.com • +1 (669) 203-7000 • https://www.linkedin.com/in/shivani-d-50a446106
January 26th, 1998 • 20192 Joseph Circle, Cupertino, CA 95014

# **Objective**

Computer Science major from UC San Diego enroute to graduate in 2020 cum laude. I seek a program that would leverage my drive, experience and motivation whilst enabling me to network, showcase my skills and push the boundaries for women in tech.

## **Education**

University of California, San Diego

September 2016-Present

B.S. in Computer Science

Taken upper division courses on Advanced Data Structures, Programming Language Theory, Artificial Intelligence, Digital Systems and Software Engineering.

Current Overall GPA: 3.54/4.00

The International School Bangalore

August 2014-June 2016

IB Programme - Secondary High School

Physics, Chemistry and Math taken as HL and Spanish, Economics and English taken as SL.

IB Score: 38/45

## **Work Experience**

Computer Science & Engineering Tutor (CSE 8A, 8B, 12, 15L, 100 & 130) September 2017-Present

University of California, San Diego Computer Science and Engineering Department

Tutored for Introduction to Java I & II, Basic & Advanced Data Structures and Object-Oriented Programming and

Programming Languages.

Estimated input time: 100 hours per quarter

Application Development Internship at Workday

June 2019-September 2019

Pleasanton

Built various REST API's for application development using the Workday proprietary language, XpressO.

Estimated input time: 40 hours per week

Quality Engineering Internship at ServiceNow

July 2018-December 2018

San Diego

Wrote many automated Selenium tests, whilst performing regular regression testing and writing small-scale scripts.

Estimated input time: 20-40 hours per week

#### Projects

## Roommate Engagement Needs Tool (RENT) App

April 2019-June 2019

Implemented the database and server-side functionality for an application that organizes and maintains living arrangements between housemates.

Total input time: 10 hours per week

2048 Al Simulator

January 2019-February 2019

Created a simulator for the 2048 game using a simple expectimax algorithm to simulate moves and game outcomes to determine how to achieve a high score.

Total input time: 8 hours per week

Restaurant Management App

August 2016-December 2017

Encoded a billing and ordering management system for a make-believe pizza joint in Visual Basic 6.0.

Total input time: 800 hours

## **Technical Languages**

Java :-	Expert	Python :-	Expert
C :-	Expert	C++ :-	Expert
JavaScript :-	Intermediate	Shell :-	Intermediate
Haskell :-	Intermediate	Prolog :-	Intermediate
HTML :-	Beginner	CSS :-	Beginner
Julia :-	Beginner	Visual Basic :-	Expert
Fisher constitution Activities			

# **Extracurricular Activities**

- Trained Western singer-song writer; performed at mall inaugurations and starred in music videos.
- Completed 9 years of professional kathak training: performed publicly on several occasions and taught children aged 9-15 kathak basics.
- Volunteered at Kundanahalli Gate School to teach English and Mathematics to students from an underprivileged background.

## **Achievements**

#### Programming Assignment

March 2017-April 2017

- Selected in top 10 from 300 students for an in-class programming competition.
- Created a defence, evasion and attack strategy for a virtual gaming entity.